

Full Stack Developer

Los Angeles, CA (715) 441 1884 jacobkmiller@icloud.com jacobkmiller.com

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in back end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including JavaScript, Python and Ruby.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python

Ruby

Javascript

HTML5

CSS3

Jquery

Node.js

Express.js

Angular.js

MongoDB/Mongoose

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Django

Rails

Github

PERSONAL SKILLS

Fast Learning Organization Creativity Teamwork

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013

B.A. in Environmental Science U.C. Santa Barbara

LINKS

www.jacobkmiller.com https://github.com/Jacobkmiller https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-miller-32908445

PROJECTS

DOC 2 DOC (October 2016 – Present)

Description: Rental Web App Providing a forum for the lending and renting of medical equipment between licensed professionals.

Built With: Ruby on Rails, Google Maps Javascript API, JQuery, JQuery UI, PostgreSQL, Materialize, Stripe API **Role:**

- Generated backend functionality.
- Implemented Google Maps Javascript API
- Customized JQuery UI Datepicker
- Incorporated Stripe API

DRONE SQUAD (September 2016)

Description: Social Web App for Drone Enthusiasts. **Built With:** Node.js, Express, Mongoose/MongoDB, Angular.js, Materialize, Google Maps Javascript API, Instagram API **Role:**

- Built backend API to serve data to Angular app.
- Made CRUD functionality for Users, Events, and Groups.
- Incorporated Instagram API into our Angular app

EXPERIENCE

TEACHING ASSISTANT - CODING DOJO

(November 2016 - January 2017)

Address questions, present demonstrations and assist students.

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER (October 2016 - Present)

- Interface with clients to determine project requirements.
- Develop custom websites using Ruby on Rails

ENVIRONMENTAL SPECIALIST - ST.CROIX ENVIRONMENTAL (2013 - 2016)

- Created, edited and analyzed geographic data
- Updated/produced maps for contaminated sites
- Updated/Maintained our geographic database
- Collected data in field such as GPS and water samples